Guide to the Maurice C. Burritt Director of Extension papers, 1919-1924.
Burritt, Maurice C., Director of Extension papers, 1919-1924
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Maurice C. Burritt Director of Extension papers, 1919-1924.
21-24-101
Maurice C. Burritt
3.2 cubic feet.
Correspondence and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and other records of the Director of Extension at the New York State College of Agriculture.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence and other records of the Director of Extension at the New York State College of Agriculture. Topics include services for farmers, fruit and vegetable growers, and homemakers; other New York State agricultural organizations; New York State counties; and reports on the current state of the New York State College of Agriculture and its extension program. Included is a photograph album illustrating the overcrowded conditions in the New York State College of Agriculture as of 1920.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Burritt, M. C. (Maurice Chase); New York State College of Agriculture.
Subjects:
Agricultural extension work -- New York (State); Home economics extension work -- New York (State); University extension -- New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Papers, 1919-1922
  - "The Rise and Significance of Agricultural Extension," Annual Report for 1921-1922 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "The Work and Needs of the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University," 1919 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - New York State College of Agriculture, "Reports of Committees Presented to the College Conference, Cornell University Semi-Centennial, June 20, 1919" (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reports and minutes on the needs of the New York State College of Agriculture, November-December 1919 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "The Extension Service: An Outline of the Field Organization," Extension Bulletin 63, April 1923 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photograph album showing congested conditions at the New York State College of Agriculture, February 1920 (Box 4, Volume 1)
- Papers, 1922-1923
  - Adams, Professor B. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Agriculturist E.R. Eastman Birge Kinne (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - American Farm Bureau Federation O. E. Bradfute (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Atwood, M. V., Publications (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ba (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barrus, Professor M. F., Plant Pathology (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Be (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bee Specialist (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bi-Bl (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Burritt, Professor M. C. - addresses (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - C (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Canon, Helen, Associate State Leader (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Club Agent Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Conference - Annual A. R. Mann Martha Van Rensselaer (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Conference - Regional (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Memorandum on Conference on Special Forms of Extension (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cooperatives (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Coryell, Jay - State County Agent Leader (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - County Agricultural Agents (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - County Conference Board (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dairymen's League News (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - E (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Empire State Potato Growers' Cooperative Association L. J. Steele (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Extension Directors (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Extension Report (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - F (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fairs and Farmers' Field Days, 1923 J. Wright (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Farm Bureau Federation E. V. Underwood S. L. Strivings (Box 1, Folder 31-33)
  - Farrand, President Livingston (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Federal Land Bank - Springfield, Mass. Edward H. Thomson (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Federation Sheep Associations (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Fuel Situation, Material concerning (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - G (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Geneva Experiment Stations (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Grange League Federation Exchange, Inc. (GLF) W. L. Gay H. E. Babcock (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Grange (State) (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - H (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Agricultural Handbook Material (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Health Exposition (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Hay Grading and Inspection W. A. Wheeler (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Home Bureau Federation Mrs. A. E. Brigden, President (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Home Demonstration Agents (city) (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - J (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - L (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Ladd, Professor C. E. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Long Island Poultry Project James E. Rice (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - M (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - McKenzie, H. C. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Maple Producers' Cooperative Association, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Mann, A. R. (Box 1, Folder 55-58)
  - N (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - New York Canning Crops Cooperative Association Thomas E. Wright (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - New York Cooperative Poultry Certification Association (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - New York Cooperative Seed Potato Association, Inc. B. P Jones (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - New York Holstein-Friesian Association E. A. Zimmer (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - New York Horticultural Society (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - New York State Canners' Association (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - New York Seed Improvement Cooperative Association, Inc. B. P. Jones (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - New York State Fruit Testing Cooperative Association (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Niagara Falls International Exposition (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Oneida County Situation' Correspondence re (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - P (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Pageant: "In Partnership with the Farmers" (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Potatoes - Grading and Marketing E. V. Hardenburg (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Radio (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Rice, Professor J. E., Poultry (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Robinson, Professor Montgomery (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - S (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sanderson, Professor Dwight, Rural Social Organization (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Schumaker, Doris, Associate Home Demonstration Agent (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Simon, Lloyd., Assistant State Leader (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Soil Improvement Committee, National Fertilizer Association W. D. Hurd (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Specialists, Material concerning H. E. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Stevenson, H. A. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - T (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - United States Department of Agriculture C. W. Pugsley (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - V (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Van Rensselaer, Miss Martha, Home Economics (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
  - W (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Warren, G. F. and farm Management (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Weather Bureau Forecasts for Farmers (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
  - Westchester County Material (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Wheeler, Professor R. H. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - White, Professor E. A. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - White Pine Blister Rust L. H. Goddard A. F. Amadon (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
  - Wright, Professor W. J., Junior Extension (Box 2, Folder 24-27)
  - X-Y (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Papers, 1923-1924
  - American Agriculturist E. R. Eastman (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - American Bankers' Association Conference L. D. Greene (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - American Farm Bureau Federation J. W. Coverdale (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Atwood, Professor M. V. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - B (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
  - Burritt, M. C. (Personal) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - C (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Coryell, Jay (County Agent Leader) (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
  - Counties A-C (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Counties D-H (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Counties J-N (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Counties O (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Counties R-S (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Counties T-Y (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - County Club Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - D (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Dairy Building Federation (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence - Dairymen's League D. J. Carter T. E. Milliman (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Demonstration Cars (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Dunn, P. L. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - E (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Empire State Potato Growers' Cooperative Association L. J. Steele (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - F (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Fairs - State and County (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Farmers' Institutes, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Farmers' Field Days, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Farm Bureau Federation E. V. Underwood (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Farrand, President Livingston (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Federal Land Bank E. H. Thomson (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Forestry Research Council (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Fruit and Vegetable Growers (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - G (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - State Grange (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - GLF Exchange H. E. Babcock (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - H (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Home Bureau Federation (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Home Demonstration Agents Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - I (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Inspection - Certification (Box 3, Folder 9-Aug)
  - J-L (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Long Island - Farmingdale (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - M (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Mann, A. R. (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
  - Maple Producers' Cooperative Association, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - N (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - National Council of Farmers' Cooperative Marketing Association (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - New York Agricultural Society (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - New York Canning Crops Cooperative Association Thomas E. Wright (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - New York Cooperative Seed Potato Association, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - New York Holstein-Friesian Association (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - New York Horticultural Society (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - New York Seed Improvement Cooperative Association, Inc. B. P. Jones (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - New York Sheep Association (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - New York State Cabbage and Potato Growers W. B. Farrar (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - O-P (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Parker, G. W. (Business Office) (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - R (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Radio (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Reforestation Charles A. Taylor (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Robinson, Professor M. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - S (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Sodatol Leonard E. Allen J. Coryell (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Spray Service (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - State Schools (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - T (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - U-V (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - United States Employees Compensation Commission (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Van Rensselaer, Professor Martha (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Veterinarian, Extension (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - W (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Warburton, Director C. W. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Wayne County Soil Survey, Correspondence re E. R. Wagner (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Weather Bureau Forecasts Walter Magee (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - White Pine Blister Rust (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Wilson, M. C. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Witter, Hon. D. P. (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Wright, Professor W. J. (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Young, Paul R. (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Aswell Bill Walter Magee (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Collingwood, G. H. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Conservation Commission H. H. York (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Cooperative Use of Purebred Sires (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - County Agents and Agriculture Teachers, Committee of (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Dairy specialists New England States Conference (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Education (General), Department of Ray Snyder (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Farm and Home Bureau Law, Amendment to Daniel P. Witter (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Land Grant College Association (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - National Farm Forestry Extension Committee Harris A. Reynolds (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Poultry Extension Work (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Pyrke, Commissioner Berne A. (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Rural School Bill (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Smith, C. B. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Trucks (Box 3, Folder 66)